Finding Aid for the Alberto Sánchez de Iriarte Collection [Spanish Civil War]
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Series VII: Miscellaneous, Spain
  - Arts, Music, Politics, Tourism and Other, 1931-1934
    - Art Catalogs
      - Círculo de Bellas Artes, Exposición de Fotografías Naturales, Cecilio Paniagua (Fine Arts Circle, Cecilio Paniagua Natural Photography Exhibition) Catalog, Madrid, June 1934 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Círculo de Bellas Artes, Exposición de Dibujos Joaquín Talaverón (Fine Arts Circle, Joaquín Talaverón Drawing Exhibition) Catalog, Madrid, June 4, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Círculo de Bellas Artes, Exposición de Pinturas José Segura Ezquerro (Fine Arts Circle, Painting Exhibition, José Segura Ezquerro), Catalog, Madrid, June 4-13, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Círculo de Bellas Artes, Exposición de E. Martín Y. (Fine Arts Circle, E. Martin Y. Exhibition), Catalog, Madrid, June-July 1934 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Círculo de Bellas Artes, Exposición de Escultura Taurina Antonio Navarro ( Fine Arts Circle, Antonio Navarro Bullfighting Sculpture Exhibition), Catalog, Madrid, June 14, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Círculo de Bellas Artes, Exposición de Dibujos Fernando Bosch (Fine Arts Circle, Fernando Bosch Drawings Exhibition), Catalog, Madrid, October 1934 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Círculo de Bellas Artes, Exposición de Pinturas y Dibujos Ramón Calsina, Catálogo (Fine Arts Circle, Ramón Calsina, Paintings and Drawings Exhibition) Catalog, Madrid, October 1934 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Cuadernos de Maestros Japoneneses (Notebooks of Japanese Maestros, Kakemono Drawings Exhibit), Flyer, Madrid, Undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Exposición Cerámicas Peyró en el Gran Kursaal Marítimo de San Sebastián, Catálogo (Ceramic Exhibition of Peyró in the Grand Kursaal Sea Port of San Sebastian, Spain) Catalog, August 1934 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Exposición Ismael Blat (Ismael Blat Exhibition) Catalog, April 1-7, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Exposición M. López Garabal (M. López Garabal Exhibition), Catalog, September-October 1934 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Museo del Arte Moderno, Exposición de Benjamín Palencia (Modern Art Museum, Benjamín Palencia Exhibition), Catalog, May 1932 (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Unión Ibero-Americana, Exposición de Pinturas Cuenca Muñoz (Ibero-American Union, Cuenca Muñoz Painting Exhibition) Catalog, Madrid, May 1932 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Music Programs
      - Biblioteca Musical Circulante (Circulating Musical Library, Broadside, Madrid), Undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - Concierto de Piano por José Cubiles (Piano Concert by José Cubiles, Program), March 26, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - Concierto en Honor al Cuerpo Diplomático, Programa, Teatro de la Zarzuela (Concert in Honor of the Diplomatic Corps, Program, Zarzuela Theater), Madrid, April 13, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - Monumental Cinema, Orquesta Sinfónica de Madrid, con el Pianista José Cubiles (Monumental Cinema, Symphonic Orchestra of Madrid with the Pianist José Cubiles), Program, February 21 (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - Monumental Cinema, Orquesta Sinfónica de Madrid, Concierto Extraordinario (Monumental Cinema, Symphonic Orchestra of Madrid, Extraordinary Concert), Program, February 28 (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - Programme de Musique (Music Program, Regino Sáinz de la Maza and José Cubiles), February 17, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - Nicanor Zabaleta, Harpista (Nicanor Zabaleta, Harpist), Program, Undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - Teatro María Guerrero, Coro de los Maestros de Moravia (María Guerrero Theater, Choir of the Moravia Teachers) Program, Madrid, January 12, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 26)
      - Teatro Municipal, Rosa Arciniega, Programa (Municipal Theater, Rosa Arciniega, Program), Undated (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Politics
      - Constitución de la República Española (Constitution of the Spanish Republic), 1931 (Box 17, Folder 28)
      - Propaganda: “A las Mujeres Españolas, Acción Republicana (To the Women of Spain, from Republican Action, Left Party), Undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
      - Propaganda: Acción Popular, “Votad a las Derechas, Votad Contra el Marxismo” (Popular Action, Vote Right, Vote Against Marxism”), Undated (Box 17, Folder 30)
      - Propaganda: Candidatura para Diputados a Cortes de Izquierdas Republicanas (Candidacy for Deputies to Courts, Republican Left), Undated (Box 17, Folder 31)
      - Propaganda: Candidatura Republicana para Diputados a Cortes- Madrid (Capital), (Republican Candidacy for Deputies to Courts to Madrid (Capital)),Undated (Box 17, Folder 32)
      - Propaganda: “Ciudadanos Madrileños” (Citizens of Madrid), Republican-Socialist Party, Propaganda, Undated (Box 17, Folder 33)
      - Propaganda: “Madrileños” (Citizens of Madrid), Right Parties, Undated (Box 17, Folder 34)
      - Propaganda: Coalición Radical y Derechas Republicanas (Radical Right Republican Coalition), Undated (Box 17, Folder 35)
      - Propaganda: “Mujeres!”, Acción Republicana Radical Socialista Independiente y Federal (Women! Popular Action, Socialist Independent and Federal, Left Party), November 1933 (Box 17, Folder 36)
      - Propaganda: “Mujeres Españolas: Balance de una Etapa Trágica (“Women of Spain: Balance of a Tragic Stage”), Socialist Party, Undated (Box 17, Folder 37)
      - Propaganda: “Mujeres”, Votad a los Socialistas (“Women”, Vote Socialist), Undated (Box 17, Folder 38)
      - Propaganda: Partido Republicano Conservador (Conservative Republican Party), Undated (Box 17, Folder 39)
      - Propaganda: Tradicionalistas y Renovación Española (Traditionalists and Spanish Restoration, to Women and Mothers to vote for the Right Party), Undated (Box 17, Folder 40)
      - Propaganda (Second Round): A los Comerciantes, Industriales y Agricultores (To Traders, Industrialists, and Farmers), 1933 (Box 17, Folder 41)
      - Propaganda (Second Round): Candidatura para Diputados a Cortes por Madrid (Candidacy for Deputies of Courts to Madrid), Listings, Undated (Box 17, Folder 42)
    - Tourism
      - Balneario de Sierra Elvira, Temporada Oficial, del 16 de Julio al 16 de Octubre (Sierra Elvira Beach Town; Official Season, July 15-October 16), Pamphlet, Spain, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 43)
      - Centro de Atracción y Turismo, Plano y Guía de San Sebastián (Center of Attractions and Tourism; Plan and Guide of San Sebastian) Brochure, Spain, Undated (Box 17, Folder 44)
      - Centro de Atracción y Turismo, San Sebastián Playa y Montaña (Center of Attractions and Tourism; San Sebastian, Beach and Mountain), Pamphlet, Undated (Box 17, Folder 45)
      - Gvipvzcoa (Guipúzcua, Spain) Brochure, Undated (Box 17, Folder 46)
      - Guía de Ferrocarriles de Guipúzcua, Verano 1932 (Train Guide of Guipúzcua, Summer 1932) (Box 17, Folder 47)
    - Other
      - Clippings, Notable People in Spain, Undated (Box 17, Folder 48)
      - Clippings, Notable Places in Spain, Undated (Box 17, Folder 49)
      - Clippings, Spanish Culture, Undated (Box 17, Folder 50)
- Series VII: Miscellaneous, Spain
  - Conference Material, 1931-1933
    - II Conferencia Internacional de Oficinas Gubernamentales de Prensa y Representantes de Prensa (II International Conference of Governmental Press Bureau Representatives of the Press), Madrid, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Bureau International de L’Union Télégraphique (International Telegraph Union, Circular letter concerning the delivery of the signatures of the Acts of Madrid and Annexes, Berne, February 4, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Conferences Télégraphique et Radiotélégraphique Internationales, Album de Photographies (International Radiotelegraph Conference, Photo Album), Madrid, 1932 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Unión Interpalamentaria (Inter-Parliamentary Union, Statutes and Regulations 1931, Conference Preparation Guide 1933, and Correspondence (1932-1933) (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Series VIII: Miscellaneous, Latin America
  - Arts, Economy Education, Government, Literature, and Other, 1883-1935
    - Anales de la Institución Pública de Colombia, “Conferencias sobre Historia Universal” (Annals of the Colombian Public Institution “ Conferences about Universal History”), Fragment, pgs.299-308, 1883 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Boletín de Estadística de Santander (Statistical Bulletin of Santander, Colombia), Fragment and Manuscript, September, 1917 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Boletín de Estadística de Santander (Statistical Bulletin of Santander) Frament pgs. 337-356, Colombia, July 1918 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Boletín de Estadística de Santander (Statistical Bulletin of Santander) Chapters V and VI, Colombia, November 20, 1919 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Catastro de la Propiedad Raíz Gravable y No-gravable en el año 1919 (Taxable and Non-Taxable Real Estate Cadastre in 1919), Colombia (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Club Nacional de Turismo de Colombia, Mapa de Vías de Comunicación (National Tourism Club of Colombia, Transportation Networks Map) (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Elogios de Cuidades (Compliments of Cities), Fragment, pgs. 109-110, Colombia, Undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Gaceta Comercial, “Impuesto Sobre la Renta (Trade Gazette, “Income Tax”), Fragment, pgs. 15-18, Colombia, May 1917 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Gauckler, “La Memoria: El Ritmo y la Simetría”, (The Memory: Rhythm and Symmetry), Fragment, pgs. 134-136, Undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Informe del Comisario de la Goajira (Report of the Commissioner of the Guajira), Fragment, pgs. 101-109, Colombia, April 26, 1920 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Informe del Gobernador de Santander ( Report of the Governor of Santander), Fragment, pgs. 549-554, Colombia, June 14, 1920 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - La Escuela Primaria (The Primary School), Fragment, pgs. 19-24, Colombia, January 2, 1923 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - La Escuela Primaria (The Primary School), Fragment, pgs. 17-40, Colombia, January 1924 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - La Niñez (Childhood), Fragment, pgs. 87-90, April 5, 1924 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Las Declaraciones y los Decretos de las Cortes de Cádiz sobre América (Declarations and Decrees of the Courts of Cadiz about America, Madrid), 1912 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Manuscripts, “Museo de Bellas Artes, Bilbao” (Museum of Fine Arts, Bilbao), Undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Manuscripts, “Santander”, Colombia, 1917 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Manuscripts, R del Valle Inclán, “Aromas de Leyenda (Aromas of Leyend)”, Undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Manuscripts, “Unamuno”, Undated (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Martin, William, “¿ Ha Cumplido la Liga su Misión?”, La Reforma Social (Has the League Fulfilled its Mission? The Social Reform), Fragment pgs., 290-295, Cuba, August 1927 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Memoria de Gobierno (Government Annual Report), Fragment, pgs. 129-134, Colombia, 1919 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Merchán, Jorge, “Historia de la Educación en Colombia (History of Education in Colombia)”, Fragment, pgs. 480-487, July-August 1935 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Mimeographs, Juan de la Cierva, Inventor of the Autogyro, Undated (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Mimeographs, Juan Lacomba, Undated (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Motivos Colombianos, “Informe Sobre la Situación Económica del Departamento de Santander, (Colombian Motives, “Report on the Economic Situation of the Department of Santander”), Fragment, pgs. 149-152, 1923 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Motivos Colombianos, “Proceso de la Nacionalización de las Ideas Políticas en Colombia (Colombian Motives, Process of the Nationalization of Political Ideas in Colombia)”, Fragment, pgs. 157-164, June 15, 1923 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Pérez, Felipe, “Los Grandes Líricos Españoles, (There Great Spanish Lyricists), Fragment, pgs. 309-330, Colombia, Undated (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Renacimiento, “Glosario” (Renaissance, “Glossary”), Fragment pgs. 371-378, September 1907 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - “Santa Fé y Bogotá, “La Casa de las Azuolas” (Santa Fé an Bogotá, The House of the Azuolas), Fragment, pgs. 311-318, November 1923 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Typescripts, “Pueblitos del Cantábrico” (Cantabrian Villages), Spain, Undated (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Typescripts, Poems about the Monastery of Escorial, Spain, Undated (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Other: Selected Short Stories by Alberto Sánchez de Iriarte (Dr. Mirabel)
    - Clippings, Colombia, 1917 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Clippings, Colombia, Undated (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Clippings, Colombia, Undated (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Clippings, Colombia, Undated (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Clippings, Colombia, Undated (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Clippings, Colombia, Undated (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Clippings, Colombia, Undated (Box 19, Folder 38)
- Oversized Boxes
  - Magazines, Spain, 1935-1938
    - Labor Defender, September 1936,Vol. 10, No. 9 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Labor Defender, October 1936,Vol. 10, No. 10 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Photo History, War in Spain, April 1937, Vol. 1 No. 1 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Photo History, Labor Challenge, July 1, 1937, Vol. 1, No. 2 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Photo History, War is Here, October-December 1937, Vol. 1 No. 3 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - The Fight Against War and Fascism, April 1935, Vol. 2, No.6 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - The Fight Against War and Fascism, November 1935, Vol. 3, No. 1 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - The Fight Against War and Fascism, January 1936, Vol. 3, No.3 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - The Fight Against War and Fascism, February 1936, Vol. 3, No.4 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - The Fight Against War and Fascism, October 1936, Vol. 3, No. 12 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - The Fight Against War and Fascism, November 1936, Vol. 4, No. 1 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - The Fight Against War and Fascism, December 1936, Vol. 4, No.2 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - The Fight Against War and Fascism, January 1937, Vol. 4, No.3 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - The Fight Against War and Fascism, February 1937, Vol. 4, No.4 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - The Fight Against War and Fascism, March 1937, Vol. 4, No.5 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - The Fight Against War and Fascism, April 1937, Vol. 4, No.6 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - The Fight Against War and Fascism, June 1937, Vol. 4, No. 8 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - The Fight Against War and Fascism, July 1937, Vol. 4, No. 9 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - The Fight Against War and Fascism, September 1937, Vol. 4, No. 11 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - The Fight Against War and Fascism, October 1937, Vol. 4, No. 12 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - The Fight Against War and Fascism, November 1937, Vol. 5, No. 1 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - The Fight for Peace and Democracy, April 1938, Vol. 5, No. 6 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Books, Bulletins Magazines, Maps, and Newspapers, 1937-1938
    - Creixams, Pere, “Infants”, Illustrated book with lose plates, Barcelona, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Le Journal de Barcelone (The Journal of Barcelona), Paris, April 30, 1937, Year 1, No. 83 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Spanish Revolution, Bulletin Published by the United Libertarian Organizations, New York, July 2 1937, Vol. 1, No.21 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Spanish Revolution, Bulletin Published by the United Libertarian Organizations, New York, September 30, 1937, Vol. 2, No.2 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Spanish Revolution, Bulletin Published by the United Libertarian Organizations, New York, December 20, 1937, Vol. 2, No. 7 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Spanish Revolution, Bulletin Published by the United Libertarian Organizations, New York, January 10, 1938, Vol. 2, No. 8 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Spanish Revolution, Bulletin Published by the United Libertarian Organizations, New York, January 24, 1938, Vol. 2, No. 9 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Spanish Revolution, Bulletin Published by the United Libertarian Organizations, New York, February 5, 1938, Vol. 2, No. 10 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Spanish Revolution, Bulletin Published by the United Libertarian Organizations, New York, March 21, 1938, Vol. 2, No. 11 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Sunday Worker Map of Spain, January 1937 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Tierra y Libertad (Land and Freedom) September 3, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Oversized Folder
    - Poster: Tres Frentes de Lucha, Primer Frente (Three Fighting Fronts, First Front), National Confederation of Labour, CNT-AIT (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Poster: Tres Frentes de Lucha, (Three Fighting Fronts, Second and Third Fronts), National Confederation of Labour, CNT-AIT (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Poster (Detail of folded red, blue, and black shirts) (Box 21, Folder 3)